Guide to the George and Olwen Lloyd papers, 1940-1985 MVC0010.MS
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George and Olwen Lloyd papers
1940-1985
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MVC0010.MS
1 Linear Feet 1 document box and 1 flat box
George LLoyd was the fourth president of Mount Vernon Seminary and Junior College, originally founded in Washington, D.C. in 1875. His wife, Olwen Lloyd, was Headmistress of the Seminary. Mount Vernon Seminary and College merged with The George Washington University in 1999. This collection contains correspondence, and administrative files from the collection of Mrs. and Mrs. Lloyd, President and Headmistress of Mount Vernon Seminary and Junior College from 1936-1962.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired by GWU upon merger with Mount Vernon College. Collection transferred to Foggy Bottom campus in 2009.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, photographs, a plaque, and administrative files belonging to George and Olwen Lloyd, President and Headmistress of Mount Vernon Seminary and Junior College from 1936-1962. The materials in this collection range in date from 1940-1985.
Biographical / Historical
George Lloyd was named President of Mount Vernon Seminary and Junior College after the resignation of Jean Dean Cole in 1936. That same year, his wife, Olwen Lloyd was named Headmistress of the Seminary. Under their leadership, the division between the Seminary and Junior College was clarified, the Seminary curriculum was divided into two tracks: a General Course and a College Preparatory Course, and the Junior College was accredited by the Board of Education. The Lloyds oversaw the seizure of Mount Vernon's campuses, including the main Nebraska Avenue campus, by the Nacy during World War II. The Lloyds directed the packing and moving of Mount Vernon Seminary and Junior College to Spring Valley during 1942 and 1943 and facilitated the construction of a new 21-acre campus located on Foxhall Road using money granted to the college by the Navy in compensation for the military takeover of its property.
Mrs. and Mrs. Lloyd retired at the end of the 1961-1962 school year, after 30 years at Mount Vernon.
Women's colleges; Women -- Education; Mount Vernon College; Mount Vernon Seminary
- "A school which hath foundations" - address given by Mrs. Lloyd, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with Peter Pelham, 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Diamond Jubilee Papers (written by one of the LLoyds), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- George Lloyd's papers, speeches, information, including his death, 1940-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter of accreditation sent to George Lloyd, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Papers, correspondence, 1961-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Papers, correspondence, 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Papers, correspondence concerning seizure of Nebraska Ave. campus during World War II, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Papers, correspondence concerning seizure of Nebraska Ave. campus during World War II, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Papers of Olwen Lloyd, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Photos of George and Olwen Lloyd, circa 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Plaque, Olwen Lloyd presented by the class of 1950 Lois La Motte, Sc. (Box SHARED Box 22, Box 2)
  World War, 1939-1945; Women -- Education; Women's colleges; Mount Vernon College; Mount Vernon Seminary